## Gagan Malvi

## Platform and Systems Engineer

malvigagan@gmail.com +91 944-91-16454 https://malvi.me Vellore, Tamil Nadu

A capable developer working on Android platform and Linux internals. Works with Qualcomm and MediaTek chipsets, and their BSPs, with over 4 years of collective experience. Familiar with system administration and programming, and a recognized developer at XDA-Developers.

### Languages

English - Fluent Hindi - Intermediate

#### Education

# B.Tech in Computer Science and Engineering

*VIT*, *Vellore* 2020 - 2024

Current CGPA: 8.36

#### XII (Senior Secondary), CBSE

Sri Chaitanya, Bengaluru 2020

Percentage: 91.4%

#### X (Secondary), CBSE

Kendriya Vidyalaya NAL, Bengaluru 2018 Percentage: 91.0%

## Experience

#### Paranoid Android - Systems Engineer

#### Jul 2020 - present

- Brought up and maintained Android devices on AOSPA/CodeLinaro/CodeAurora codebases, worked on improving performance and overall user experience on these platforms, with help from the team.

#### **ACM-VIT - Technical Director**

#### Mar 2022 - present

- Helped set up and coordinate recruitment of freshers.
- Managing and guiding all technical departments and advising the Board on infrastructure and related technical aspects required for the function and stability of the chapter.

#### FloMobility - Platform Engineer

Jan 2023 - May 2023

- Helped set up and coordinate the development of the operating system platform for FloEdge, an outdoor grade powerful edge computer that is ready to deploy for any robotics and AI applications.

#### Teracube Inc - Platform Engineer

Feb, 2021 - Mar 2023

- Spearheading Teracube Open Devices getting all our devices to work on AOSP with open source trees. Working on platforms MT6765 and MT6771.
- Working on the Android 12 platform update for the Teracube One; feature parity, and performance improvements.
- Working on MediaTek BSPs (10, 11, 12) to provide software updates for Teracube smartphones, and working on aftermarket operating systems for the same, including certification testing for GMS.

### **Projects**

#### The Styx Project

https://github.com/StyxProject

August 2020

- A lightweight AOSP-based aftermarket distribution aiming to provide speed, stability, enhanced battery, reduced bloat and the subtly-enhanced beauty of stock Android to users.
- Features many improvements to AOSP to improve performance, and overall user experience.
- Supported by over 30 devices across 5 OEMs.
- Many improvements over AOSP to improve privacy and security.
- Supported Android versions: Android 11, 12.

#### Cobra

https://github.com/gaganmalvi/cobra-cli

February 2023

March 2021

- A proof-of-concept intrusion prevention system making use of KVM, libvirt, and QEMU.
- Calculates performance metrics and determines if the system is under attack, and blocks the attack accordingly.
- Part of a university course project.

#### Arcadia Linux

https://github.com/arcadialinux

- A Linux-based distro aiming for speed, performance and a great overall experience on portable devices and workstations.
- Based on Arch Linux, purely made to learn about Linux internals and to create a distro that would be perfect for the end user.

Other projects

https://github.com/gaganmalvi

#### Certifications

LFD103: A Beginner's Guide to Linux Kernel Development (The Linux Foundation) Issued Sep 2021

Show credential